Achmad Qoddri

Cirebon, West Java, 45156 | +62821-2036-9557 | goddri@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/goddri

ABOUT ME

I am a Physics graduate from Institut Teknologi Bandung, specializing in Computational Photonic Physics. With almost three years of experience as a physics teacher for High school and TPB (first year ITB students). I love helping others understand the wonder of physics. I am proficient in math and able to apply knowledge of physics to solve complex problems. I have also studied Web Programming, Data Science, and Machine Learning. Now, I am ready for a new adventure and excited to dive into the world of Information Technology.

SKILLS

- English (Professional Working Proficiency)
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Programming (Python, MATLAB, JavaScript, SQL, PHP)
- Teaching

- Creative
- Leadership
- **Problem Solving**
- Teamwork

WORK EXPERIENCES

Smart Privat

Part-time

Sept 2023 - Present

• Teaching Physics for High School and first year of ITB students.

Photonics Computational Laboratory Research Assistant

Full-time

Oct 2023 - Nov 2024

- Doing simulations of scattering of electromagnetic waves in nano particles using MATLAB and COMSOL.
- Investigated the scattering response of silicon nanospheres in an aggregate structure.

Lecturer Assistant

Feb 2023 - May 2024

- Create questions and solutions for homework and guizzes in several Lectures. (Elementary Physics, STOM, and Quantum Physics)
- Demonstrate physics experiments during class lectures.

Student Center for Learning

Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

• Teaching Elementary Physics for first year of ITB students.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

Asian Physics Symposium

Oct 2023

 Actively assist fellow committee members in completing required tasks, such as decoration, registration, logistics, and documentation.

SCoMOA - Lab Works Assistant

July 2023

• Enhanced communication, presentation, and problem-solving skills by explaining complex scientific concepts to students.

ISMOA - Manage Event Venue

July 2023

• Responsible for overseeing all aspects of venue selection, preparation, and coordination.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Physics

Aug 2019 - Oct 2024

- GPA: 3.23/4.00
- Silver Medal Physics-Astronomic Student Olympiad 2020
- Gold Medal Mathematics Diponegoro Science Competition 2020

SMAN 1 Sumber

Natural Science

May 2016 - June 2019

- Best Student runner-up Class 2019
- Second place National Science Olympiad (OSN) 2018 in Physics -Cirebon District

COURSES & CERTIFICATION

Codepolitan

Fullstack Web Developer

Oct 2024 - Present

- Create Portofolio, Coffee Shop, and Wedding Invitation Website.
- Learning Frontend and Backend Framework (React and Laravel) with some projects (Split Bill, Shipping Website, Online Shop, and E-Wallet).

Kaggle

Data Science and Machine Learning Oct 2023

- · Learning Data Science to visualize, analyze, and predict the future data for decision-making purposes.
- Learn Machine Learning and create speech recognition with backpropagation algorithm.